Hi everyone. In this video, I'll show
you how to customize Blitzet to fit your
workflow perfectly by exploring
preferences and key customization
options. To open preferences, click the
cog icon in the top right corner of the
app. You can also access preferences
quickly during a focus session by
clicking the same cog icon in the top
right of the Blitz panel. First is blitz
panel customization. The Blitz panel is
your main focus session interface. If
you have multiple monitors, you can
choose which screen the Blitz panel
appears on. And you can also select
whether the panel appears on the left or
right side of your screen, whatever
suits your setup best. Blitz supports
both dark and light themes to reduce eye
strain and match your preferences. You
can toggle between these modes here or
set Blitz to automatically follow your
devices theme.
Here you can choose whether to hide or
show estimated time and time taken on
tasks to keep your workspace clean or
detailed. If you hide them, you can
still see this data by hovering over a
task. In Blitz mode settings, you can
enable Pomodoro mode. Set your preferred
work sprint length and break times and
the timer will automatically switch
between them when a task is live based
on these settings. You can also set a
default brake length for a station when
you manually switch to break. Plus,
there is a scrolling title feature on
the live timer. This lets you read long
task titles fully during Blitz mode.
Next, you can personalize how Blizzard
keeps you on track. Enable timed alerts
during tasks to get regular reminders
with sound and optional animation. You
can also customize how often you get
this alerts by picking your preferred
alert timing, for example, every 30
minutes.
Here you can choose the sound you prefer
as notification sound and select the
volume. Personally, I like it to be
quiet but still be present because this
feature really helps me stay focused.
Here you can enable alerts for all
notifications which include task due
reminders, task or break times and
pomodoro sprint ends. You can choose a
sound and preferred volume level here as
well.
Blitz it lets you add a bit of fun and
motivation when you finish tasks.
You can enable the success screen to see
a motivating success message after
completing a task. You can add a fun
gift to your success screen for some
extra encouragement and choose a
celebration sound that plays every time
you check off a task. Victorious, right?
That's an overview of how to customize
Blitzet to your liking. We will continue
to add more preferences over time,
giving you even more control to
personalize your experience with
Blitzet. If you found this video
helpful, check out our other tutorials
and join our Discord community which is
supportive and always well mostly
productive. Happy blitzing.